# SAMPLE ENGINEERING

City, State Zip | 937-555-5555 | imasample@cedarville.edu | www.linkedin.com/yourname

### **SUMMARY**

Sophomore mechanical engineering student with strong interpersonal skills seeking to obtain an internship in my respective field. Passionate about the world of 3D printing and the rapid design/prototyping process. Goals include gaining real-world experience and working in the space exploration industry. Additional skills include:

- 4+ years 3D Printing Experience
- Statistics and Dynamics
- SolidWorks & Fusion 360

- Mechanics & Materials
- **MATLAB**

First Aid/CPR Certified

# **EDUCATION**

# **ABET Accredited Cedarville University**

Cedarville, OH

BS Mechanical Engineering; GPA: 3.59

Anticipated 05/2023

Minor: Bible

Honors: Dean's List (all semesters); Chancellor's Excellence Scholarship

Relevant Coursework: Statistics and Mechanics of Materials; Computational Methods; Dynamics

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Elmer W. Engstrom School of Engineering and Computer Science

Cedarville, OH

Truss Competition

08/2019-Present

 Collaborated with a 3-person team to design a truss using 100 popsicle sticks and a bottle of glue. Truss was lightest in the competition, spanned a 15" gap, and held 130 pounds.

# Cardboard Canoe Race

Worked with a 4-person team to design and build a canoe with a 40' roll of cardboard and a roll of packing tape. Placed 2<sup>nd</sup> overall in the race portion of the project.

### TSteel 8620 Heat Treating Project

- Heat treated steel alloy for tempered, annealed, and normalized properties using heat-treatment procedures.
- Tested each material for tensile strength and hardness as well as observed and photographed microstructure to compare experimental results with published data.

Doordash Cincinnati, OH **Delivery Driver** 06/2019-Present

- Manage time effectively to make deliveries, maintain high customer satisfaction, and build brand reputation.
  - Develop and utilize strong attention to detail and customer service skills through client interactions.

#### **Ozone Zipline Adventures** Oregonia, OH

Zipline Guide

05/2019-12/2019

- Trained new guides on how to inspect gear to ensure items were in good working order.
- Obtained First Aid/CPR certification as well as completed intensive ropes course training.

### Name of Company

City, ST

Your Position mo/year-mo/year

### **ACTIVITIES**

Intramural Sports – 2019–Present

Habitat for Humanity Volunteer – Summer 2020

Humanitarian Service Trip to Mexico City - Summer 2019

### SAMPLE #2

# SAMPLE ENGINEERING

CURRENT ADDRESS

Cedarville, OH 45314 (937) 766-1234 PERMANENT ADDRESS

City, ST 12345 yourname@cedarville.edu

# **Job Target: Mechanical Engineer**

Senior mechanical engineering student and accomplished intern seeking to utilize strong technical and organizational skills in the areas of design and implementation. Looking to apply training and developed skills for the benefit of the company by obtaining a position that provides meaningful work and continuous learning. Key skills include:

SolidWorks 2D CAD Drafting Matlab CNC Milling

CNC Lathing MIG and TIG Welding Six-Sigma Green Belt 2D Toolpath Creation

5S Organization Safe PIT Operation Technical Sketching Carpentry
Caglia Software Manufacturing Laster Optic Maintenance Microsoft Office

### **EDUCATION**

### Cedarville University (ABET Accredited)

Cedarville, OH | 05/2021

Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering; GPA: 3.77

Honors: Chancellor's Scholar Award; Dean's List (Fall 2019; Spring 2020; Fall 2021)

### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

## **Innotec Corporation** | *Mechanical Engineering Intern*

Zeeland, MI | 05/2020-08/2020

Optional: Use this space to give a short summary of the company and your main job responsibilities (what you were hired to do). Save your accomplishments and achievements for the bullet points below.

- Organized cell to achieve highest 5S audit scores in the company and a leader in 5S practices.
- Co-led a team of interns to reduce 100K+ a year in station interventions.
- Built various prototypes and devices to test new processes and to improve production machines.
- Ran, maintained, and performed troubleshooting on production lines.

# Name of Company/Project, etc. | Your Position

City, ST | mo/yr-mo/yr

- Explain major responsibilities/duties within the company, emphasizing accomplishments/achievements.
- Begin your bullets with action words such as "Assisted, Demonstrated, Improved, etc."

### **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE**

#### **ELMER W. ENGSTROM SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING & COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Cedarville, OH

# Senior Design Project – Liberia Solar Water Heater | Team Member

01/2021-05/2021

- Worked with a team to fully engineer a solar water-heating system for a Liberian missionary hospital.
- Created a sustainable design, applying the concepts of appropriate technology.

### **SAE Supermileage** | *Team Member*

01/2020-04/2020

• Participated in collegiate competition that challenges engineering students to build a one-passenger vehicle that performs far above industry standards in automotive efficiency.

### **Aluminum 7075-T651 Heat Treating Project** | *Team Member*

08/2019-09/2019

- Heat treated aluminum-zinc alloy for underaged, aged, overaged, and annealed properties using common heattreatment procedures.
- Tested each material for tensile strength and hardness as well as observed and photographed microstructure to compare experimental results with published data.

# **ACTIVITIES**

Tau Delta Kappa (Honors Society) – 4 years; Habitat for Humanity Volunteer – Summers 2019, 2020; Mentoring Program Small Group Leader – 2 years; Intramural Sports – 3 years; Humanitarian Service Trip to Nicaragua – Summer 2019